[
    {
        "question": "1",
        "answer": "The responsive behavior of dogs also caught the attention of an evolutionary anthropologist, Brian Hare."
    },
    {
        "question": "2",
        "answer": "He conducted an experiment to see how dogs would respond to human gestures compared to wolves, who share the same common ancestor."
    },
    {
        "question": "3",
        "answer": "He placed two cups on the ground with food hidden under only one of them."
    },
    {
        "question": "4",
        "answer": "When he pointed to the cup with the food, the dogs found it easily."
    },
    {
        "question": "5",
        "answer": "The wolves, however, struggled and chose cups at random, paying no attention to his gestures"
    },
    {
        "question": "6",
        "answer": "Dr. Hare concluded that the dogs’ ability to read human gestures allowed them to perform better than the wolves."
    },
    {
        "question": "7",
        "answer": "He explained that dogs, unlike wolves, have developed communicative skills with humans and a sense of friendliness."
    },
    {
        "question": "8",
        "answer": "This explanation sounds reasonable according to several evolutionary biologists."
    },
    {
        "question": "9",
        "answer": "They say that from the common ancestors of these two species, those that acted friendly toward humans evolved into dogs, and those that didn’t became wolves."
    },
    {
        "question": "10",
        "answer": "Furthermore, Dr. Hare suggested that the friendly nature of dogs probably provided them a survival advantage that allowed their population to grow larger than that of wolves."
    }
]